Guide to the Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Communism, Socialism, Trotksyism TAM.505
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Communism, Socialism, Trotskyism
2007-
TAM.505
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
112.0 websites 1.2 TB.
The Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Communism, Socialism, Trotskyism, was created with the Web Archiving Service from the California Digital Library. (The Web Archiving Service was made possible with support from the National Digital Information and Infrastructure Preservation Program and the University of California, as part of a project to preserve born-digital political communication.) The Tamiment Library creates topically based archives of periodically captured websites documenting labor and left activity, principally that based in the United States, with a particular focus on New York City. This collection contains periodically archived websites of (principally) Marxian inspired entities, including political parties, that identify with or are inspired by Communist, Socialist, or Trotskyist perspectives. While the focus is on the United States, selected international sites, especially those documenting the history of these movements, are also archived. NOTE: For technical, privacy and other reasons, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. NOTE: if a link for an individual site does not work, click on the TITLE of this collection (in the descriptive summary section at the top of the Guide) which will take you to the web archive, then go to the site list and then the web site(s) you wish to view.
Tamiment Library.
Scope and Contents
This web archive contains periodically archived websites of (principally) Marxian inspired entities, including political parties, that identify with or are inspired by Communist, Socialist, or Trotskyist perspectives. While the focus is on the U.S., with a particular focus on New York City, selected international sites, especially those documenting the history of these movements, are also archived.
Classic Marxian doctrine advocates collective ownership of the means of production, to be achieved by the political struggle of the working class via political parties and labor unions, and the eventual withering away of the state.
For the purposes of this archive, Communist organizations are understood as those that supported or now align themselves with the ideology and politics of the former Soviet Union and the associated international Communist movement that arose in the aftermath of the Russian Revolution of 1917, or with the Chinese revolution (Maoism), or other schisms in the international Communist movement; Trotskyist organizations are those rooted in Leon Trotsky's critique of the Soviet Union, which he helped to found; Socialist organizations, including social democratic organizations (progressive organizations with socialism as an ultimate, if distant goal), include those rooted in the pre-1917 socialist movement, and reject the Communist ideal of a one-party state.
NOTE: For technical, privacy and other reasons, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl.
NOTE: if a link for an individual site does not work, click on the TITLE of this collection (in the descriptive summary section at the top of the Guide) which will take you to the web archive, then go to the site list and then the web site(s) you wish to view.
Historical/Biographical Note
The Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Communism, Socialism, Trotskyism, along with other topically based web archives relating to labor and the left, was created with the Web Archiving Service from the California Digital Library. This service employs open source web archiving utilities developed by Internet Archive with the support of the The International Internet Preservation Consortium. The Web Archiving Service was made possible with support from the National Digital Information and Infrastructure Preservation Program and the University of California, as part of a project to preserve born-digital political communication. The role of the Tamiment Library during this project and thereafter was/is to create topically based archives of websites documenting contemporary and ongoing labor and left activity, as well as the history of labor and the left, principally in the United States, with a special concentration on New York City.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
A list of related Tamiment Library web archives, whose ns2:titles all begin with the prefix "Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left), can be found at the website Web Archives from New York University Libraries.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Arrangement
Websites are arranged alphabetically.
Communist Party of the United States of America.; Engels, Friedrich, 1820-1895; Lenin, Vladimir Il'ich, 1870-1924; Mao, Zedong, 1893-1976.; Marx, Karl, 1818-1883; Trotsky, Leon, 1879-1940.; Communism |x History.; Communism |z United States.; Communism.; Communist parties |z United States.; Communist parties.; Communists |z United States.; Communists.; Marxism |x History.; Socialism |x History.; Socialism |z United States.; Socialism.; Socialist parties |z United States.; Socialist parties.; Socialists |z United States.; Socialists.; Soviet Union |x History.; Soviet Union |x Politics and government.; Trotskyism |x History.; Trotskyism |z United States.; Trotskyism.; Trotskyist parties |z United States.; Trotskyists.
- Communism, Socialism, Trotksyism Web Archive, 2007-
  - Act Now to Stop War and End Racism (ANSWER), Jul 2009-present
  - Against the Current, Solidarity, May 2011-Nov 2012
  - American Communism and Anticommunism: A Historian’s Bibliography and Guide to the Literature, Jul 2009
  - Arguing the World | PBS Online, Aug 2009
  - Brecht Forum, Jul 2009-present
  - Committees of Correspondence for Democracy and Socialism, Aug 2009-present
  - Communist Party of the United States of America, May 2008-present
  - CPGB Bibliography, Jan 2010
  - CPUSA: Southern California Communist Party, Aug 2010-Jan 2012
  - Demarcations Journal of Communist Theory and Polemic, May 2012-present
  - Democratic Socialists of America, Nov 2008-present
  - Dialectical Marxism: The Writings of Bertell Ollman, Jul 2009-Feb 2013
  - Dissent Magazine, May 2012-present
  - Early American Marxism: A Repository of Source Material, 1864-1946, Sep 2009-present
  - Encyclopedia of Trotskyism Online (ETOL), Dec 2008-present
  - ernie124102, Apr 2011-present
  - Eugene V. Debs Foundation, Aug 2010-present
  - Fight Imperialism Stand Together, Jul 2009-present
  - Freedom Road Socialist Organization, Feb 2010-present
  - Freedom Socialist Party (U.S.), Feb 2007-present
  - Holt Labor Library, May 2012-present
  - In Defence of Marxism, Dec 2008-present
  - International Bolshevik Tendency, May 2011-present
  - International Communist League (Fourth Internationalist), Nov 2008-present
  - International Publishers, Apr 2012-present
  - International Socialist Organization (U.S.), Nov 2008-present
  - Keep On Keepin' On, Jul 2011-present
  - Labor Upfront Newsletter, May 2008-Mar 2013
  - League for the Revolutionary Party - Communist Organization for the Fourth International, Mar 2009-present
  - LeftShift.org, Apr 2009-present
  - Leon Trotsky Internet Archive, Dec 2008-present
  - Links International Journal of Socialist Renewal, Jul 2011-present
  - Lubitz TrotskyanaNet, Aug 2009-present
  - Maoist Internationalist Movements (MIM), Jul 2010-Jul 2011
  - Marxism Leninism Today, Nov 2010-present
  - Marxist Education Press Publications, May 2012-Nov 2012
  - Marxist-Humanist Initiative, Jan 2010-present
  - Marxists Internet Archive, Dec 2008-present
  - Monthly Review: An Independent Socialist Magazine, Mar 2009-present
  - National Committee to Reopen The Rosenberg Case, Jul 2009-present
  - New Politics, May 2012-present
  - New York State Communist Party, Aug 2010-present
  - News and Letters Committees, Mar 2009-present
  - Next Left Notes, Jul 2011-present
  - Niebyl-Proctor Marxist Library, May 2012-present
  - North-Atlantic Left Dialogue, May 2011-present
  - Northern California CCDS, Aug 2010-present
  - NYC Local of the Socialist Party USA, Aug 2009-present
  - NYCsocialist.org, Nov 2010-present
  - Peace and Freedom Party, Jul 2009-present
  - People's World, Aug 2010-present
  - Phillip Bonosky, Sep 2010-Feb 2013
  - Platypus Affiliated Society, Apr 2012-present
  - Progressive Labor Party, Jul 2009-present
  - PSLweb (Party for Socialism and Liberation), Aug 2009-present
  - Religion and Socialism Commission, May 2012-present
  - Rethinking Marxism, May 2011-present
  - RevLeft, Dec 2010-present
  - Revolution Books (New York, NY), Sep 2007-present
  - Revolution: Voice of the Revolutionary Communist Party, USA, Aug 2010-present
  - Revolutionary Communist Party, USA, Sep 2007-present
  - Revolutionary Workers Group, May 2011-present
  - Science and Society, May 2011-present
  - Situations: Project of the Radical Imagination, May 2012-present
  - SocialDemocratsUSA.org, Apr 2009-present
  - Socialism and Democracy Online, Apr 2012-present
  - Socialist Alternative, Mar 2009-present
  - Socialist International, May 2012-present
  - Socialist Labor Party of America, Jul 2009-present
  - Socialist Party USA, Sep 2007-present
  - Socialist Register, May 2012-present
  - Socialist Viewpoint, Aug 2009-present
  - Solidarity-US.org, Mar 2010-present
  - Spirit of Haymarket: Communist Party of Illinois Blog, Aug 2010-present
  - The Buckeye Socialist Alternative, May 2011-Nov 2012
  - The League, May 2011-present
  - The Militant, Jul 2009-present
  - Trotsky.net, Dec 2008-present
  - Viewpoint Magazine, May 2012-present
  - Weather Underground FBI Report 1976, 08/09/2009
  - Whittaker Chambers, Jul 2011-present
  - Workers World, Jul 2009-present
  - Workers World Party, Jul 2009-present
  - World Socialist Web Site, Apr 2012-present
  - Young Communist League USA, Mar 2009-present
  - Young Democratic Socialists, Nov 2008-present
  - Young People's Socialist League, Sep 2007-Nov 2010
  - Young People's Socialist League Reunion, Sep 2007-May 2008
  - Youth for International Socialism, Dec 2008-present